Your mission, should you choose to accept it,
is to go ahead and refactor the users page
that we've been working on,
and this time you're going to use script setup
to trim down some of that code.
Then if you have any props or admits you want to practice with,
go ahead and do that and otherwise,
keep on moving stuff in,
playing around, seeing how you feel.
Welcome back everyone. How was the exercise?
If anyone had any questions about how that went,
please be free to drop that inside of the chat.
In the meantime, I'll go ahead and run through that solution.
All right, so switching back to say love you.
And then run dev, great.
Great, all right.
So we don't need to see what's happening right now,
so we're just going to actually just full screen this
so that people can go in as far as what's going on.
So what are we doing here?
We are going to go open up our users page
and let's see what we got.
Well, everything's already been migrated
in that everything is inside of async setup,
so this is good.
So let's start by adding that setup attribute.
That's the first step to do.
Once you do that, you'll realize,
oh, okay, this is interesting.
Now we got to start deleting some stuff,
so let's start deleting that export
so we don't need that anymore.
Boom, gone.
Well, we mentioned before that all components
are automatically registered once they're imported,
so that's gone too, so we delete that.
And then finally, we already said
that the script should be set up,
so we delete this block too.
And once we do that, you'll notice that the reactive,
which was graying out earlier,
because it said it wasn't being used,
it just basically detected the scope of the object
and was like, I don't see it within the scope of the module,
but you're fine now because we've deleted all those exports.
If we save that, oh, we got one more bit actually,
we can delete the return.
And so now we can verify that everything is working
and just to make sure we can just do a one, two, three,
there you go, did update, fantastic.
Now the only other thing too,
is that we just want to practice really quick
using the define props and emits.
The way that would work is let's go ahead
and then say const props equals define props,
and we could say something like title, for example,
and type string, and then we can do a default
of users.
And so to show that this works, we'll come inside of here,
and let's start by saying this is a test.
So we test, great, and we can swap this out now for title.
Refresh, there we go.
Now, something was brought up though,
regarding wait a second,
how did you call define props without importing it?
And more importantly, let me fix this part first,
you'll notice that because we're not actually
calling props anywhere,
there's no actually need to do that,
so you can actually just leave it off like this right now.
So, but the question here around define props,
why is it not yelling at us
that we don't know what this is looking for?
So the reason this is the case
is because when you're inside of script setup,
basically the compiler knows
that these specific functions are gonna exist.
So in other words, define props and define emits,
which I actually didn't clarify earlier,
is only specific to script setup.
If you try using define emits
to find props inside of an options API,
that'll just break, because why would you?
If you're in options API leveraging the setup,
then you should already be using the other options.
And so in other words,
the compiler knows that it's technically already a global,
so treat it like a global import for this.
That said though, I personally am typically a fan,
especially if this is a newer code base,
to just leave the import explicit.
That way no one knew is like, wait, what's going on?
There's no assumed knowledge here, we're good.
So why is reactive not like that?
Why is reactive not like that?
So we delete that and save.
The reason for that is because reactive cannot be assumed
in this context that it will be imported.
So in other words, to think of it another way
is that when this code is built and compiled,
define props basically just reverts back
to its normal stuff.
Like there's, if it's not detected,
it'll get taken out basically.
So there's some kind of optimization happening.
I can't explain the details of it,
but there's a reason why the fine props is okay,
but then other helper methods like ref, reactive,
view cannot intelligently guess those things.
So as a result, it forces you to be very explicit
that you want to use these helper methods.
So yeah, they're called, I think,
compiler-specific helper functions, but anyways.
And then the other thing we go on in practice
is define emits, and that we can just say,
once again, we can say something like update user list.
And so you can imagine how would that work
if a user clicked a button, that update user list,
it would send it to the parent.
Maybe it has to send some new data down.
That's how that basically might be working.
Okay, nope, I think we're good.
Oh, that's the thing.
In the event anyone here is coming from Vue2,
and if you're using Vitor as your VS Code extension,
just a reminder to go ahead and basically disable
and install that when you're working on Vue3 projects
going forward, because Volar and Vitor
will basically collide.
So just wanted to make that note.
Oh, here we go.
By the way, you see this?
So this is just like a small, let you know,
defined props, it's a compiler macro,
no longer needs to be imported.
Again, it's not really gonna matter at the end of the day,
because you see that it's not actually yelling at you
inside of your code editor,
but it is trying to let you know
that it is technically a global import.